Sushant Kr. Rai

UX Designer

I am an India based UX designer and researcher with 6 years of industry experience. I help businesses to expand their capacity by connecting their untouched hidden dots because I know how to balance desirability, feasibility and viability lenses to create the most valuable user experiences for products and businesses.

www.sushantkumarrai.com sushantkumarrai7@gmail.com +91 85114 50603

LinkedIn | Behance | Dribbble

Work Experience

Google / UX Designer

Aug 2022 - Present | Bangalore, India

Improving the operational efficiency of Google's data centres.

Honeywell International / Senior UX Designer

Aug 2019 - Aug 2022 | Bangalore, India

I worked in the Honeywell Connected Enterprise (HCE)-Connected Plant domain, where my responsibilities were to deliver a world-class user experience for the Honeywell Connected Plant (HCP) portfolio.

During my tenure, I've supported **24+ major & minor product releases**, worked on **3 projects** & **10+ new product ideas**, streamlined the UX engagement process for the teams, helped teams achieve **8-figure business** through **15+ customer acquisitions**.

HCL Technologies / Senior UX Designer

Oct 2018 - Aug 2019 | Chennai, India

I Designed a Centralized Data Manager platform for Roche (Hoffmann - La Roche) in order to connect different analyzers (instruments) of the x800 family which consists of Cobas 6800/8800 and STING analyzers. I also conducted user testing sessions to analyze and measure the user experience of a product for **IEC 62366-1** regulatory compliance.

Independent Design Consultant / UX Designer

Feb 2018 - Sep 2018 | Lucknow, India

Worked as an independent design consultant on designing various new media installations, exhibition spaces and web applications for clients.

[24]7.ai, Inc. / Interaction Design Intern (AI & UX/UI)

Jul 2017 - Jan 2018 | Bangalore, India

I Designed an internal communication platform for [24]7.ai chat agents by embedding artificial intelligence(AI) into their enterprise applications to create high-performance cultures that drive organizational success.

Independent Design Consultant / UX Consultant

Jun 2016 - Nov 2016 | Ahmedabad, India

Worked on new product concepts and mobile app design for an Ahmedabad-based industrial IoT company focused on developing and implementing predictive energy and asset intelligence for industries, commercial establishments and utilities.

Education

National Institute of Design (NID)

New Media Design | M.Des.

2015 - 2018 | Gandhinagar, India

Government College of Architecture

Bachelor of Architecture (B. Arch) 2010 - 2015 | Lucknow, India

* Batch Topper & Thesis Topper

Skills

UX Research, Interaction & Visual Design, Documentation, Prototyping, New Media Design, AR/VR, Motion Design, Architectural Design.

Design Thinking & Strategy

Organizing UX Workshops, Experience Mapping, Task Analysis, Information Architecture, Brainstorming, Why/How Laddering, Wireframes, Persons, Paper Prototyping, Scenarios, Storyboarding, Sketching, Contextual Inquiry, Work Model, User Testing, A/B Testing.

Design Tools

Figma, Miro, Sketch, Adobe XD, InVision, Marvel, Adobe CC (Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, AfterEffects, PremierPro), Abstract, Balsamiq, AUTOCAD, Rhino, V-Ray, Sketch-Up.

Prototyping

Sketching, Processing, Workshop, Model Making, 3d Modelling, 3D Printing, Leaser Cutting, Arduino.

Interests

Animals, Hindi & Urdu Poetry, Arts